# CAMERON REMESZ

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I've worked as a front-end web developer for 4 years, 2 of them professionally with Angular. I put a heavy focus on solving business problems through critical thinking and teamwork. With a background management I use my communication, decision making and organizational skills to efficiently build and maintain quality software with teams. I use a user/client first approach to ensure quality UI/UX and fulfill business requirements and increase profit.

#### **REACH ME AT**

Email: cameron.remesz@gmail.com Portfolio: www.cameronremesz.com GitHub: github.com/lowkeycode

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/cameron-remesz

### **SKILLS**

- Angular
- TypeScript
- RxJS
- JavaScript
- SASS
- React Firebase
- Git/GitHub/GitFlow
- Cypress
- Java/Selenium
- REST APIs
- · Agile/Scrum

### **EDUCATION**

# Juno College Of Technology Bootcamp

Graduation Certificate | Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

Studied HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, REST APIs, Firebase, Git/GitHub, Web Accessibility, Responsive Design, Wireframing/Prototyping, Paired Programming, Team Collaboration, Public Speaking, Technical Communication

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Pulse Loyalty - View Live Project | Github Repo

JavaScript, Firebase Realtime Database, Firebase Authentication & Hosting, CSS, HTML An internal discount tracking app for real customers. Built using vanilla JavaScript with Google Firebase for user authentication/data storage. Created for a mobile mechanic company as an internal tool to help build customer retention and increase profits. Mock username: test12@gmail.com. Mock password: test12.

## Chatter - View Live Project | Github Repo

React, Sass, Firebase Auth (Google), Firebase Realtime Database

A real-time chat app with Google authentication. Built using React hooks, functional components and Google Firebase services to implement persistent data/authorization. Hosted on Netlify.

# NgRx Reactive Forms (2023) - View Live Project Github Repo

Angular (Reactive Forms), TypeScript, NgRx (Redux), Tailwind

A todo app built on my free time to learn the redux pattern of state management. My company was looking at it as an alternative to the "Service with a Subject" pattern but ultimately did not switch. I used Tailwind as I was already familiar with Bootstrap and used the reactive forms framework to stay up to date with Angular features as my company used a handmade forms framework.

## **PROFESSIONAL HISTORY**

### **Operations Manager**

MicroMech | Jun 2019 - Jun 2021

I built our supply chain and analyzed business financials to create business plans. I created a profit and loss statement from their database using SQL to ensure profitability and reduce costs. I worked with the CMO, CTO and developer team to help with app development and marketing strategies.

## **Junior Front-End Developer**

ZIRO Technologies | Mar 2022 - Present

I helped grow customer base and increase customer satisfaction/retention by implementing requested features, components and pages. I spearheaded updating application branding/styling to ensure brand cohesiveness & marketability. I migrated legacy AngularJS pages to Angular. I improved developer experience and decreased development time in the test application by implementing a mock database (idb-keyval) and an API mocking library (MSW). I maintained code quality & coverage by writing tests in Java with Selenium. I contributed to productivity of other company teams by building internal tooling by streamlining manual processes.